{
    "id": "blacksmith-gear",
    "type": "Gear",
    "name": "Blacksmith Gear",
    "cards": [
        {
            "id": "beacon-shield",
            "type": "gear",
            "name": "Beacon Shield",
            "front": "beacon-shield.webp",
            "back": "_back.webp",
            "keywords": [
                "weapon",
                "melee",
                "shield",
                "metal",
                "heavy"
            ],
            "speed": 1,
            "accuracy": 6,
            "strength": 5,
            "rules": [
                "Block 2"
            ],
            "desc": "Add <font class=\"inline_shield\">2</font> to all hit locations.<br/><b>Block 2:</b> Spend <font class=\"kdm_font\">a</font> to ignore 2 hits the next time you are attacked. Lasts until your next act. You cannot use <b>block</b> more than once per attack.",
            "sub_type": "blacksmith",
            "type_pretty": "Gear",
            "sub_type_pretty": "Blacksmith",
            "selector_text": "Beacon Shield",
            "handle": "beacon_shield"
        },
        {
            "id": "dragon-slayer",
            "type": "gear",
            "name": "Dragon Slayer",
            "front": "dragon-slayer.webp",
            "back": "_back.webp",
            "affinities": {
                "top": "blue",
                "right": "red"
            },
            "speed": 1,
            "accuracy": 6,
            "strength": 9,
            "keywords": [
                "weapon",
                "melee",
                "grand weapon",
                "two-handed",
                "heavy",
                "metal"
            ],
            "rules": [
                "Frail",
                "Slow",
                "Sharp",
                "Devastating 1",
                "Early Iron"
            ],
            "desc": "<b>Early Iron:</b> When an attack roll result is 1, cancel any hits and end the attack.",
            "sub_type": "blacksmith",
            "type_pretty": "Gear",
            "sub_type_pretty": "Blacksmith",
            "selector_text": "Dragon Slayer",
            "handle": "dragon_slayer"
        },
        {
            "id": "lantern-cuirass",
            "type": "gear",
            "name": "Lantern Cuirass",
            "front": "lantern-cuirass.webp",
            "back": "_back.webp",
            "armor": 5,
            "location": "body",
            "keywords": [
                "armor",
                "set",
                "metal",
                "heavy"
            ],
            "desc": "-2 movement.",
            "affinities": {
                "top": "blue",
                "left": "green",
                "right": "green",
                "bottom": "blue"
            },
            "affinity_bonus": {
                "desc": "When you <b>depart</b>, add <font class=\"inline_shield\">3</font> to all hit locations with metal armor.",
                "requires": {
                    "puzzle": {
                        "green": 2,
                        "blue": 2
                    }
                }
            },
            "sub_type": "blacksmith",
            "type_pretty": "Gear",
            "sub_type_pretty": "Blacksmith",
            "selector_text": "Lantern Cuirass",
            "handle": "lantern_cuirass",
            "rules": []
        },
        {
            "id": "lantern-dagger",
            "type": "gear",
            "name": "Lantern Dagger",
            "front": "lantern-dagger.webp",
            "back": "_back.webp",
            "keywords": [
                "weapon",
                "melee",
                "dagger",
                "finesse",
                "metal"
            ],
            "speed": 2,
            "accuracy": 7,
            "strength": 1,
            "affinities": {
                "right": "red"
            },
            "rules": [
                "Paired",
                "Sharp",
                "Early Iron"
            ],
            "desc": "<b>Sharp:</b> Add 1d10 strength to each wound attempt.<br/><b>Early Iron:</b> When an attack roll result is 1, cancel any hits and end the attack.",
            "sub_type": "blacksmith",
            "type_pretty": "Gear",
            "sub_type_pretty": "Blacksmith",
            "selector_text": "Lantern Dagger",
            "handle": "lantern_dagger"
        },
        {
            "id": "lantern-gauntlets",
            "type": "gear",
            "name": "Lantern Gauntlets",
            "front": "lantern-gauntlets.webp",
            "back": "_back.webp",
            "armor": 5,
            "keywords": [
                "armor",
                "set",
                "metal",
                "heavy"
            ],
            "affinities": {
                "left": "green"
            },
            "affinity_bonus": {
                "desc": "+2 accuracy with <b>club</b> weapons.",
                "requires": {
                    "puzzle": {
                        "green": 1
                    }
                }
            },
            "sub_type": "blacksmith",
            "type_pretty": "Gear",
            "sub_type_pretty": "Blacksmith",
            "selector_text": "Lantern Gauntlets",
            "handle": "lantern_gauntlets",
            "rules": [],
            "desc": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "lantern-glaive",
            "type": "gear",
            "name": "Lantern Glaive",
            "front": "lantern-glaive.webp",
            "back": "_back.webp",
            "keywords": [
                "weapon",
                "melee",
                "spear",
                "axe",
                "two-handed",
                "finesse",
                "metal"
            ],
            "speed": 2,
            "accuracy": 6,
            "strength": 4,
            "rules": [
                "Reach 2",
                "Sharp",
                "Early Iron"
            ],
            "affinities": {
                "bottom": "green"
            },
            "desc": "<b>Sharp:</b> Add 1d10 strength to each wound attempt.<br/><b>Early Iron:</b> When an attack roll result is 1, cancel any hits and end the attack.",
            "sub_type": "blacksmith",
            "type_pretty": "Gear",
            "sub_type_pretty": "Blacksmith",
            "selector_text": "Lantern Glaive",
            "handle": "lantern_glaive"
        },
        {
            "id": "lantern-greaves",
            "type": "gear",
            "name": "Lantern Greaves",
            "front": "lantern-greaves.webp",
            "back": "_back.webp",
            "keywords": [
                "armor",
                "set",
                "metal",
                "heavy"
            ],
            "affinity_bonus": {
                "desc": "+2 movement.",
                "requires": {
                    "puzzle": {
                        "red": 2,
                        "blue": 1
                    }
                }
            },
            "affinities": {
                "left": "red",
                "right": "red",
                "top": "blue"
            },
            "armor": 5,
            "location": "legs",
            "sub_type": "blacksmith",
            "type_pretty": "Gear",
            "sub_type_pretty": "Blacksmith",
            "selector_text": "Lantern Greaves",
            "handle": "lantern_greaves",
            "rules": [],
            "desc": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "lantern-helm",
            "type": "gear",
            "name": "Lantern Helm",
            "front": "lantern-helm.webp",
            "back": "_back.webp",
            "keywords": [
                "armor",
                "set",
                "metal",
                "heavy"
            ],
            "armor": 5,
            "location": "head",
            "affinities": {
                "bottom": "blue"
            },
            "affinity_bonus": {
                "desc": "Ear Plugs. You are <b>deaf</b>, -1 accuracy.",
                "requires": {
                    "puzzle": {
                        "blue": 1
                    }
                }
            },
            "sub_type": "blacksmith",
            "type_pretty": "Gear",
            "sub_type_pretty": "Blacksmith",
            "selector_text": "Lantern Helm",
            "handle": "lantern_helm",
            "rules": [],
            "desc": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "lantern-mail",
            "type": "gear",
            "name": "Lantern Mail",
            "front": "lantern-mail.webp",
            "back": "_back.webp",
            "keywords": [
                "armor",
                "set",
                "metal",
                "heavy"
            ],
            "armor": 5,
            "location": "waist",
            "affinities": {
                "right": "green"
            },
            "sub_type": "blacksmith",
            "type_pretty": "Gear",
            "sub_type_pretty": "Blacksmith",
            "selector_text": "Lantern Mail",
            "handle": "lantern_mail",
            "rules": [],
            "desc": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "lantern-sword",
            "type": "gear",
            "name": "Lantern Sword",
            "front": "lantern-sword.webp",
            "back": "_back.webp",
            "affinities": {
                "left": "red"
            },
            "keywords": [
                "weapon",
                "melee",
                "sword",
                "finesse",
                "metal"
            ],
            "speed": 3,
            "accuracy": 5,
            "strength": 3,
            "desc": "<b>Sharp:</b> Add 1d10 strength to each wound attempt.<br/><b>Early Iron:</b> When an attack roll result is 1, cancel any hits and end the attack.",
            "sub_type": "blacksmith",
            "type_pretty": "Gear",
            "sub_type_pretty": "Blacksmith",
            "selector_text": "Lantern Sword",
            "handle": "lantern_sword",
            "rules": []
        },
        {
            "id": "perfect-slayer",
            "type": "gear",
            "name": "Perfect Slayer",
            "front": "perfect-slayer.webp",
            "back": "_back.webp",
            "keywords": [
                "weapon",
                "melee",
                "grand weapon",
                "two-handed",
                "sword",
                "heavy",
                "finesse",
                "metal"
            ],
            "desc": "-2 movement",
            "rules": [
                "Slow",
                "Sharp",
                "Devastating 2",
                "Irreplaceable"
            ],
            "affinities": {
                "bottom": "red"
            },
            "speed": 3,
            "accuracy": 6,
            "strength": 14,
            "sub_type": "blacksmith",
            "type_pretty": "Gear",
            "sub_type_pretty": "Blacksmith",
            "selector_text": "Perfect Slayer",
            "handle": "perfect_slayer"
        },
        {
            "id": "ring-whip",
            "type": "gear",
            "name": "Ring Whip",
            "front": "ring-whip.webp",
            "back": "_back.webp",
            "rules": [
                "Sharp",
                "Reach 2"
            ],
            "affinities": {
                "left": "blue"
            },
            "keywords": [
                "weapon",
                "melee",
                "whip",
                "finesse",
                "metal"
            ],
            "desc": "<b>Early Iron:</b> When an attack roll result is 1, cancel any hits and end the attack.",
            "speed": 2,
            "accuracy": 5,
            "strength": 0,
            "sub_type": "blacksmith",
            "type_pretty": "Gear",
            "sub_type_pretty": "Blacksmith",
            "selector_text": "Ring Whip",
            "handle": "ring_whip"
        },
        {
            "id": "scrap-shield",
            "type": "gear",
            "name": "Scrap Shield",
            "front": "scrap-shield.webp",
            "back": "_back.webp",
            "keywords": [
                "weapon",
                "melee",
                "shield",
                "bone",
                "metal"
            ],
            "affinities": {
                "right": "red"
            },
            "rules": [
                "Block 1"
            ],
            "desc": "Add <font class=\"inline_shield\">1</font> to all hit locations.<br/><b>Block 1:</b> Spend <font class=\"kdm_font\">a</font> to ignore 1 hit the next time you are attacked. Lasts until your next act. You cannot use <b>block</b> more than once per attack.",
            "speed": 2,
            "accuracy": 7,
            "strength": 3,
            "sub_type": "blacksmith",
            "type_pretty": "Gear",
            "sub_type_pretty": "Blacksmith",
            "selector_text": "Scrap Shield",
            "handle": "scrap_shield"
        }
    ]
}